Support Admin Watch on kissasia.cam or kisskh.org
دعم الإدارة، شاهد على kissasia.cam أو kisskh.org
♪I plant miles of peach blossoms just for her♪
أزرع أميالاً من أزهار الخوخ خصيصاً من أجلها
♪Sweet words bloom upon those branches♪
♪تزهر الكلمات العذبة على تلك الأغصان♪
♪Love runs deep, trapped in longing♪
♪الحب عميق، محاصر في الشوق♪
♪Night listens answers to longing are the most terrifying♪
♪تستمع الليل إلى إجابات الشوق، وهي الأكثر رعباً♪
♪At my fingertips, worries drift and linger♪
♪على أطراف أصابعي، تتلاشى الهموم وتستمر♪
♪Having tasted a moment of carefree joy♪
♪ بعد أن تذوقت لحظة من الفرح الخالي من الهموم ♪
♪Today, I pluck romance and moonlight♪
اليوم، أقطف الرومانسية وضوء القمر
♪And weave them all into a painting♪
♪ واجمعها كلها في لوحة ♪
=The Ultimate Vow, Unknown to You=
=العهد الأسمى، الذي تجهله=
=Episode 21=
=الحلقة ٢١=
Please. I beg you.
أرجوك. أتوسل إليك.
Please save him.
أرجوكم أنقذوه.
I'm begging you.
أتوسل إليك.
She loved him so much.
لقد أحبته كثيراً.
She knelt for three days and three nights to beg for medicine.
ركعت لمدة ثلاثة أيام وثلاث ليالٍ تتوسل للحصول على الدواء.
But in the end, he killed her.
لكن في النهاية، قتلها.
Yes.
نعم.
If you knew the one you love would betray you someday,
لو كنت تعلم أن من تحب سيخونك يوماً ما،
even kill you,
بل قد أقتلك،
would you still save him?
هل ستنقذه رغم ذلك؟
I would.
أود.
Why?
لماذا؟
Because the sincerity of this very moment
لأن صدق هذه اللحظة بالذات
is worth trading a life for.
يستحق الأمر التضحية بالحياة من أجله.
Was it worth it?
هل كان الأمر يستحق كل هذا العناء؟
When you truly love someone,
عندما تحب شخصًا ما حقًا،
you don't ask whether it's worth it.
أنت لا تسأل عما إذا كان الأمر يستحق ذلك.
Congratulations on passing the second trial.
ألف مبروك على اجتياز الاختبار الثاني.
But the third trial is the hardest.
لكن المحاكمة الثالثة هي الأصعب.
Because it requires you to let go of your obsession.
لأنه يتطلب منك التخلي عن هوسك.
Are you willing?
هل أنت مستعد؟
Lead the way.
كن رائداً.
(Medicine)
(الدواء)
(Chrysanthemum)
(أقحوان)
This is my third trial.
هذه هي محاكمتي الثالثة.
This medicine can cure all poisons,
هذا الدواء قادر على علاج جميع أنواع السموم،
but it requires a life in exchange.
لكن ذلك يتطلب التضحية بحياة في المقابل.
Do you know why I have lived 90 years
هل تعلم لماذا عشت 90 عاماً؟
yet still look like a child?
ومع ذلك لا يزال يبدو كطفل؟
Because you mastered the art of preserving youth.
لأنك أتقنت فن الحفاظ على الشباب.
No.
لا.
It's because I severed love and desire.
ذلك لأني قطعت صلة الحب والرغبة.
Love ages a person the fastest.
الحب يُسرّع شيخوخة الإنسان.
Saving him will shorten your lifespan.
إنقاذه سيقصر عمرك.
Are you willing?
هل أنت مستعد؟
Qingru.
كينغرو.
To save your life,
لإنقاذ حياتك،
she paid with her own.
دفعت من مالها الخاص.
She's already gone.
لقد رحلت بالفعل.
If anything happens to her,
إذا حدث لها أي مكروه،
I will never forgive you.
لن أسامحك أبداً.
Stop!
قف!
Since you and I have met,
منذ أن التقينا أنا وأنت،
it is a pact of a hundred years.
إنه اتفاق لمدة مئة عام.
Alive, we walk together.
نسير معاً ونحن أحياء.
Dead, we return together.
بعد الموت، نعود معاً.
If you betray me,
إذا خنتني،
even in the netherworld,
حتى في العالم السفلي،
I will seek you out for reckoning.
سأبحث عنك لأحاسبك.
In this life,
في هذه الحياة،
you alone I will not fail.
لن أخيب ظنك وحدك.
♪It still falls short of the one who holds my heart♪
♪لا يزال أقل شأناً من الشخص الذي يملك قلبي♪
Fifty years have passed.
لقد مرّت خمسون سنة.
I thought I'd never be moved by anyone again.
ظننت أنني لن أتأثر بأحد مرة أخرى.
♪Commanding heroes to fight across the land♪
♪يأمر الأبطال بالقتال في جميع أنحاء الأرض♪
♪For her alone, I would claim the world♪
♪من أجلها وحدها، سأمتلك العالم♪
So you were testing us just now.
إذن كنت تختبرنا الآن.
I wanted to see
أردت أن أرى
whether you would give up your life for him,
هل ستضحي بحياتك من أجله؟
and whether he would risk everything for you.
وما إذا كان سيخاطر بكل شيء من أجلك.
♪Even with a single thunderous command♪
♪حتى بأمر واحد مدوٍّ♪
No need to test.
لا حاجة للاختبار.
My life has always belonged to her.
لطالما كانت حياتي ملكاً لها.
♪Through blood-red chaos and clamor♪
♪عبر فوضى وصخب بلون الدم♪
♪I fell for her grace between her brows♪
♪أُعجبتُ بجمالها بين حاجبيها♪
♪Lowered my gaze, gentle just for her♪
خفضت نظري، بلطفٍ من أجلها فقط.
♪I plant miles of peach blossoms just for her♪
أزرع أميالاً من أزهار الخوخ خصيصاً من أجلها
♪Sweet words bloom upon those branches♪
♪تزهر الكلمات العذبة على تلك الأغصان♪
♪Love runs deep, trapped in longing♪
♪الحب عميق، محاصر في الشوق♪
♪Night listens answers to longing are the most terrifying♪
♪تستمع الليل إلى إجابات الشوق، وهي الأكثر رعباً♪
♪At my fingertips, worries drift and linger♪
♪على أطراف أصابعي، تتلاشى الهموم وتستمر♪
♪Having tasted a moment of carefree joy♪
♪ بعد أن تذوقت لحظة من الفرح الخالي من الهموم ♪
Cui Di.
من هو دي.
I'll take you out of here.
سأخرجك من هنا.
♪And weave them all into a painting♪
♪ واجمعها كلها في لوحة ♪
♪Today, I pluck romance and moonlight♪
اليوم، أقطف الرومانسية وضوء القمر
Yuwen Que.
يوين كيو.
Tell me,
أخبرني،
why did you return to Mobei back then?
لماذا عدت إلى موبي في ذلك الوقت؟
At the time, my father ordered me to marry Princess Wen Ling.
في ذلك الوقت، أمرني والدي بالزواج من الأميرة وين لينغ.
I would rather give up my status as a prince,
أفضّل التخلي عن مكانتي كأمير،
only to ask Father's permission.
فقط لطلب إذن الأب.
Preposterous!
أمرٌ سخيف!
For a common woman,
بالنسبة للمرأة العادية،
you would abandon your royal identity?
هل ستتخلى عن هويتك الملكية؟
Yes. To me, Ru
نعم. بالنسبة لي، رو
is far more important than royal status.
أهم بكثير من المكانة الملكية.
Guards!
حراس!
Escort the Crown Prince to Chengguang Hall.
رافق ولي العهد إلى قاعة تشنغوانغ.
Without my decree,
بدون مرسومي،
he is not to take a single step outside.
ممنوع عليه أن يخطو خطوة واحدة خارج المنزل.
So
لذا
you were imprisoned.
لقد سُجنت.
Yes.
نعم.
My father ordered me to marry Princess Wen Ling.
أمرني والدي بالزواج من الأميرة وين لينغ.
To escape the marriage, I went to the battlefield.
للهروب من الزواج، ذهبت إلى ساحة المعركة.
When I finally escaped,
عندما تمكنت أخيراً من الهرب،
I heard about what happened to your mother.
سمعت بما حدث لوالدتك.
And you were nowhere to be found.
ولم يكن لك أثر في أي مكان.
Then why didn't you tell me?
فلماذا لم تخبرني؟
I didn't want our identities to stand in our way.
لم أكن أريد أن تقف هويتنا عائقاً في طريقنا.
I thought as long as I gave up my status as a prince,
ظننتُ أنه طالما تخلّيتُ عن مكانتي كأمير،
we could live in peace together.
يمكننا أن نعيش معاً بسلام.
In fact, those rumors were deliberately spread by His Majesty.
في الحقيقة، تم نشر تلك الشائعات عمداً من قبل جلالته.
What did you say?
ماذا قلت؟
His Majesty didn't want to see you fall in love with a Mobei prince,
لم يرغب جلالته في رؤيتكِ تقعين في حب أمير من موبي،
so he deliberately released assassins from Mobei to kill her.
لذلك قام عمداً بإطلاق سراح قتلة من موبي لقتلها.
He just didn't expect that you would...
لم يكن يتوقع أن تفعل ذلك...
So,
لذا،
all of this was orchestrated by him alone?
هل كان هو وحده من دبر كل هذا ؟
Just to...
فقط لـ...
Even His Majesty didn't expect that this move
حتى جلالته لم يتوقع أن تكون هذه الخطوة
would doom you beyond redemption.
سيحكم عليك بالهلاك الذي لا رجعة فيه.
Stop talking.
توقف عن الكلام.
Actually, you later found out as well
في الواقع، اكتشفت ذلك لاحقاً أيضاً.
that my mother was killed by my own father.
أن والدتي قُتلت على يد والدي.
Why did all of you hide it from me?
لماذا أخفيتم الأمر عني جميعاً؟
Yuwen Que.
يوين كيو.
Do you know how much I've hated you all these years?
هل تعلم كم كرهتك طوال هذه السنوات؟
I know. I'd rather you hate me.
أعلم. أفضل أن تكرهني.
I only want you to live.
كل ما أريده هو أن تعيش.
You're no match for the Emperor.
أنت لست نداً للإمبراطور.
I don't want to watch you die for revenge.
لا أريد أن أشاهدك تموت انتقاماً.
Why?
لماذا؟
Why did he treat us like this?
لماذا عاملنا بهذه الطريقة؟
Di.
من.
I bought this at the market.
اشتريت هذا من السوق.
They say it wards off evil.
يقولون إنها تطرد الشر.
Young lady, you're the best.
يا آنسة، أنتِ الأفضل.
After all these years,
بعد كل هذه السنوات،
you still keep it?
هل ما زلت تحتفظ به؟
Young lady, I...
يا آنسة، أنا...
Let bygones be bygones.
عفا الله عما سلف.
Actually, all these years,
في الواقع، طوال هذه السنوات،
I was ordered by the Emperor to protect you and your mother.
لقد أمرني الإمبراطور بحمايتك أنت ووالدتك.
So all these years of friendship were merely a duty?
إذن، كل هذه السنوات من الصداقة كانت مجرد واجب؟
No.
لا.
I never...
لم أفعل ذلك أبداً...
Cui Di.
من هو دي.
Our bond ends here.
تنتهي علاقتنا هنا.
Young lady, please listen to me.
يا آنسة، أرجو أن تستمعي إليّ.
From this day on,
ابتداءً من هذا اليوم،
we are no longer friends.
لم نعد أصدقاء.
All these years, it was thanks to Cui Di staying by your side.
كل هذه السنوات، كان ذلك بفضل بقاء كوي دي بجانبك.
She's the person I trust the most.
إنها الشخص الذي أثق به أكثر من غيره.
More than me?
أكثر مني؟
The dignified Crown Prince of Mobei,
ولي عهد موبي المحترم،
actually getting jealous of my female guard.
أشعر بالغيرة من حارستي.
In front of you,
أمامك،
I am only Yuwen Que.
أنا فقط يوين كيو.
Young lady, I'll take my leave first.
يا آنسة، سأستأذن أولاً.
By the way, I want to see your sword.
بالمناسبة، أريد أن أرى سيفك.
This is the Cangyu Sword.
هذا هو سيف كانغيو.
Forged from refined steel of Cangzhou and quenched with jade.
مصنوع من الفولاذ المكرر من تسانغتشو ومقسى باليشم.
But isn't the Cangyu Sword...
لكن أليس سيف كانغيو...
That's right.
هذا صحيح.
It's a tribute sent from Cangzhou to Mobei every year.
إنها لفتة تقديرية تُرسل من تسانغتشو إلى موبي كل عام.
Only five exist in the entire realm.
لا يوجد سوى خمسة منها في المملكة بأكملها.
Yuwen Que.
يوين كيو.
Don't blame me.
لا تلومني.
Young lady, you can't enter the palace.
يا آنسة، لا يمكنكِ دخول القصر.
Step aside.
تنحى.
He is the Emperor,
هو الإمبراطور،
your biological father.
والدك البيولوجي.